Hello and welcome to the Junkyard Love Podcast.
Well, I kind of interrupted you by hitting record.
My apologies there, man, but, um, you're.
Kind of just in the process of.
Of telling me about how, like, having.
Having a kid like,changed your relationship with God
Is kinda kind of like what we were talking about.
It changed.
It changed everything, bro.
Like I said, I just.
I just.
I'm.
I'm there for for the births.
Like, I'm very.
Like, I'm.
I'm right.
I'm right in the mix, bro.
Like, I'm right there.
Like, I haven't pulled one out yet, but ideally that would be the plan, um, at some point, but, yeah, I just.
I just don't see how you can receive again a child and just not believe that this, that this is magical and this comes straight from source.
Like, even just on the craziest level of just biology, like, how is it that we're created so perfectly, right?
And so, you know, I gave.
And, you know, this is so different.
I feel like just even from you and me catching up from even the pods we've done before, if anybody ever, you know, has seen that or know me, but, you know, nobody really knows this side of me.
And that's why I've kind of taken, like, a little break from social media and posting and being out, you know, in the mix and being outside, as I like to call it, because I'm trying to find my footing in this whole new life that I live.
And, you know, what is it?
Like?
I know that it's super important to men especially to, like, represent something.
Like, it's very important.
It's very
A part of, like, the masculine being to be like, all right, I represent this.
Like, I'm gonna take it.
I'm, um, you know, I'm taking across the finish line, right?
I'm taking the, I'm carrying the burning torch
and here we go.
It's super important.
And.
And, um.
Um, I feel like, you know, I had that before with the bike, but it was a very false sense of self accomplishment.
Right?
And I have, um, a great relationship with like, the man that I used to be.
And as far as, like, I was so close to being the right man, yet just.
Just change directions a little bit, right?
So it's like, um.
And again, you know, all kind of like what we were touching on before.
And I don't even.
I don't know if we just want to keep going or what, but, um, the man just everything I.
I just gave myself credit for everything and, uh, and.
And I just felt so fraudulent about that.
I really did.
Like, I.
Now I look back, I even believed that the bike was from God.
I really do.
Because it's like at that moment in that point in my life, I was gonna commit suicide.
So all of a sudden this thing shows up and I'm so invested in it and I love it so much.
It just keeps me around.
Like, I, I don't know, bro.
I just have a hard time wrestling with that idea that, that I just don't believe in coincidence.
Right?
Do you, do you see?
Like, I think about it with myself too.
Uh, like, as much as I know now that, like, wow, I'm so glad that those things didn't become my long term.
I know that I was exposed to and opened up to much more broad things than what I thought I was meant for at that time or whatever.
Do you see it, uh, do you see it as a very integral part of who you are today, though?
Like, do you.
For me, it's hard.
As much as I want to have this magic thing in my head, I'm like, oh, if I could rewind time and not do that, I wouldn't.
I'm, uh, not like that at all.
I see that, like, I had to go through those things, and those were clearly the lessons that I needed to get to this version of myself.
Do you feel the same way?
No, I.
100%.
One, I.
I think that.
I think men for.
And this is, you know, I try to stick on certain things.
Like, I feel like people in general, like, we can go a little broader.
But I think men specifically, um, only because that's what I'm experiencing.
Right.
Is we find our spirituality climbing the mountain.
I always have this, like, funny joke with my wife is just like, you know, she can come out of the bedroom after reading scripture and she's just bawling her eyes out, and it's just so magical and all this kind of stuff.
And I'm just like, I don't experience that when I read the book.
Like, I just don't.
You know what I mean?
But like, when it snows and it's 25 and I'm in the river, I'm like, oh, here he is, bro.
Like, oh my gosh.
Like, I feel you.
Like, and it's just like I'm as far as just like, you know, rewinding a little bit with the bike.
Like I said.
I always have just given myself credit and I've just always felt, uh, this sense of like, you're kind of not a Fraud.
Like, I'm like, I am who I say I am.
I know I show up.
Like, there's not nobody that can look at me and say, you're not doing what you say you do.
Like, there's.
There's no part about that.
Everything was always, like, out there.
Like, you know, you say you put in this kind of work and you say you do this and you say you do that, and there you are.
You know, let me pause that.
And, you know, that was never, that was never a question, but the question was, like, why does this thing happen?
You know?
And like I said, I Jake.
And you know, high sight's always 2020, right?
So, you know, looking back, like, I'm like, that came to me, that kept me alive.
And I feel like that was the gift.
It was like, oh, my gosh, bro.
Like, you really are serious about this.
Like, you're really thinking about that.
You're really thinking about taking your life.
Like, let me give you.
Let me give you a distraction for a few years and then you'll figure it out.
And that's what it was like.
You know, uh, my wife jokes now.
Um, I mean, I drink an ungodly amount of caffeine, bro.
Like, ungodly.
And she's just like, why is this necessary?
And I just thought, I thought, I thought.
I'm like, because it's the only thing that I know is not the best for me, that I don't kick.
You know what I mean?
Because I'm like, I'm mad disciplined with the food and all these other things in the gym and all this stuff.
And I'm just like, I know it's not the best.
And I'm just like, I found peace in chaos.
So that, uh, heart pumping adrenaline thing that I feel at home, that's why.
I.
Yeah, you've worked there.
Exactly.
You spent a lot of hours in that spot.
Not only did I spend a lot of hours there, but I.
I spent peace there, right?
So it's like this comfort within this, like, chaos of just adrenaline and all these things that was, like, so attached to the bike that it created such a great relationship too.
And also, too, you know, the bike was the ability for me to have an out that wasn't my fault.
That never happened.
Right?
So perfect.
I'll just go as hard as I can on this thing.
This thing will take me out.
It's not even my fault.
And it just never happened.
Not only did it never happen, I have video proof that I can send you that you can pop in here.
Of somehow this guy's rolling around on the freeway, he rolls twice, and he lands on his feet multiple times.
Right?
Or a bike runs into a bus station, and somehow I just fall off at the last second, land on my feet.
Like, it just.
Like I said, bro, I just look back, and I'm just.
Like, something had its hand on me, you know what I mean?
And I just.
I have a hard time not going or saying, like, that was all me.
Yeah.
Like, give me the credit here.
I'm the guy, you know?
Um.
So I wrestled with that for a while, bro.
And that's why, like I said, I feel like there's a lot of what I was a few years ago is just not there anymore, you know?
Yeah.
I mean, I.
I think a lot about.
Like, I've been doing this podcast because I started it pre pandemic, so it's been, like.
It's been a little over five years.
And, um, I mean, you were like.
You were Amongst my first 50, and you came on multiple times.
You were reoccurring.
So, like, we were.
In a weird way, we were going through a lot of similar stuff together.
Um, and it's interesting, though, because, like, I actually.
I was typing a wall of text to you when we were texting just, like, last week or whatever.
And, uh, I didn't hit send because it just kept going on.
I feel like this is something that could just continuously.
It's hard to land on what exactly am I trying to say?
But, uh, there is, like, I.
I have.
I don't want to listen back to those episodes.
Um, I'm not ashamed of those episodes, but it's m.
Almost an unrecognizable version of me.
Like, it's.
It's almost like, in a lot of ways, dude.
And what's crazy for me is, like, I.
I was going through a lot of, like, deeply spiritual and trauma stuff as well.
Like, I was going through basically a spiritual psychosis, and I just put a mic in front of me and had my friends come over, you know, and so, like, yeah, it's beautiful.
So.
So all that to say as much as there's like, oh, man, I don't really.
Like, if you pulled a clip up from that time and said, like, hey, what do you think about this?
I'm probably gonna have a different input now.
But I also see the way that if I hadn't done those things and been so vulnerable myself, I wouldn't be where I'm at with this podcast where people are comfortable now to be, like, completely Vulnerable.
Uh, it's created a space, like, without me even trying, I've created, like, uh, this space for other people to come and just completely, like, lay it down and be authentic.
Yeah.
I don't know.
In the podcast space, it, uh, I don't know, it could get cheesy quick and it could feel like people are trying to sell you stuff.
But, you know, I'm 100, 111 episodes in, and I've, you know, it's all, it's all been free.
I've never tried to sell anybody anything.
It's just been, yeah, facts.
Here's me and the people around me and the people that I'm meeting and, like, what we're going through, and hopefully it helps, you know, Facts.
Yeah, I like that.
Yeah.
Um, well, so I, I, I thought about what's useful to people, because I'm sure there's a good handful of people who have listened to the other episodes and, and that's awesome.
But, uh, as far as.
Let's, like, rewind a little bit.
People who absolutely have just clicked on it.
Yeah.
We were just cooking, bro.
And we were just jumped right in.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, so, so let's, let's set a stage and bring in some newcomers, like, hey, you know, wave to all of our friends.
I'm sure we have plenty of Pacific Northwest people who know both of us.
Hello.
But you're going to hear some repeats from us, uh, for a few minutes anyway, so.
Welcome to the podcast, brother.
Appreciate you, bro.
Yeah, I'm excited to be here.
I'm excited to run it back.
This will be, I think that this will be the fourth time, bro.
We did one.
We did two.
Two doo.
And then we did one with my guy Matt, remember?
Yeah.
That was amazing.
Yes.
This would be the fourth time.
That was a blast.
Well, anybody can go check out those.
I mean, there's certainly, like, we've grown as men and, and, uh, 100%.
It's been a while, but those, there's some good, valuable, valuable stuff in those older episodes, so.
I agree.
Uh, Nate, man, will you give me just, like, kind of a, A bio?
I know it's an impossible question, but will you fill us in if we don't know who you are?
Yeah.
Uh, wow.
And it's funny because we were just talking right before he turned the camera on or where if this is going to start, about how, um, I'm in a phase where I'm trying to find my footing again.
Right.
I identified with one thing, um, which was stunt riding for a Very long time.
I, um, spent 10 years of my life dedicating my entire life, all, All.
All my time, all my money, all my energy to one thing that, um, I feel like is just now a piece of me and not the whole bit of me.
So, you know, to give a bio, man, I.
I'm working on that, right?
I'm working on a new one.
Um, I'm.
I'm a.
I'm a new dad.
Um, three kids, uh, under four years.
Um, husband, married, working on that.
That's my main focus is my family and my marriage right now.
Um, the last time we spoke, man, um, I was managing a restaurant, um, fully full entrepreneur, um, run a content agency.
Fantastic.
Um, been the thing that I needed, I feel like, to pull.
To.
To pull the dog back out of me from, like, kind of getting out of the bike and into something new.
It's just like, you know, put your back up against the wall and have mouths to feed and not know where the next check's coming from, you know?
Um, I feel like these are the type of moments that I needed to actually find, which is kind of what we were talking about before was my spirituality.
Because I just kept leaning on myself, right?
Like, you know, believe in yourself.
Like, do.
Do this yourself, yourself, yourself, yourself, yourself.
And I feel like that is so the narrative of self help, social media, like, you know, all this, like, motivational guru stuff, which I used to be that guy.
Like, I.
That was my M.O.
was like, yo, I did this, like, you know.
You know, and I just found.
I always found that.
And we know this, right?
We've had even this conversation, you know, years past, that the finish line is always like, after you, like, break the tape and you get that, uh, it's empty, right?
So it's like, what if I know this, right?
And I'm fortunate, Jake.
And I think this is something where I feel like I'm going to be a testimony towards is I reached a place previously, like, we had this conversation where 99.9 of people ever get in their life, and that's, will you find something in this life that you're willing to die for?
And not only are you willing to die for it, but willingly die for it, Right?
I mean, I used to tell my mom, mom, I love you.
If I pull out this driveway and I don't come home, don't be sad.
Why?
Because I wanted to be doing this.
This is what.
This is how I wanted to go.
Okay?
What that means is death, or the thought of death is where you really come alive.
This is like.
And honestly, what I didn't even know when I was thinking about this the other day and while.
When we were gonna pod is.
And I didn't think of this until I was running a mile in 20 degree weather.
Like we were just talking about before is the thought of death and being okay with death is true faith.
Think about that.
Like, you cannot be willing to go out like me and jump over the handlebars on the highway going 70 miles an hour if you don't believe that something's there to cover you.
What do you think people.
What do you think other people think of death?
Why is it.
I.
I think that people are often fearful of death and we avoid the very thought of it.
Uh, even though it's one.
It's.
Even though it's actually one of the only promises that there is here.
Think about it.
What's.
Like, we're always.
That's what we're always.
Jake, you know this, right?
We've had these conversations.
Everybody wants, like, the guarantee and the comfort and.
And the.
The routine and all this kind of stuff.
Guess what?
The promise here is that you're going to.
You're going out.
So the fact that we're afraid of the only actual promise actually stops us from the full experience here, right?
And again.
So kind of what I was saying before is I actually went through this phase when I was, like, first, uh, awakening, right, and first having kids.
Like, okay, well, the man before which we had spoke about, the liar, the cheater, the deceiver, the, you know, the breaking the law, running from the cops, doing all this, doing all that, causing trouble for no good reason at all, he has to die.
And it's only true to some extent, right?
It's not he has to die.
It's what can.
How do you evolve him, right?
It's like I, uh, look at it like a sculpture, right?
Like, okay, this sculpture looks good, but how can we make this, you know, for lack of a better term, like Greek God?
Can we chisel him more, right?
Like, I just.
I need more in the obliques, bro.
You know what I mean?
Like, I need a little more.
The shoulders are kind of lacking.
You know what I mean?
It's the same sculpture, right?
But it's more chiseled, it's more developed, I think is a great word.
So I went through this phase where, man, this is just, uh, you know, scripture says boast in your weaknesses.
Um.
I was kind of docile because I'm like, okay, he's dead.
Nasty Nate is dead, okay?
Now what?
Who?
Okay, so, okay, how does, how do I navigate this, right?
And it's like, no, he doesn't die.
He, he, he evolves.
What was the word I just used?
He, uh, he develops.
Okay, so the same thing.
And I, man, I wrote this caption the other day, bro, and this perfectly describes.
What do they say about simplicity, right?
Um, as simplicity being the most powerful thing, I wrote this caption and I could send it to Jake.
And this is something I said for my son's birthday.
And I tried, and I just wrote out paragraphs and paragraphs and paragraphs.
And I was like, okay, how can you get this into a couple sentences, right?
Any parents out there?
The first thing, being a father, right?
Would I want my son to be proud, to model me as a man?
Right?
And would I want my daughter to marry a man like me?
If you need to ask any other questions, I don't.
Then you are, you are lost, right?
Right?
Thinking about it, if my daughter brought me through the door, am I going to be like, oh, God, like, we have an issue, or am I going to be like, he's going to take care of her, right, man?
Um, and my son, right?
Like, man, is he gonna go, God, you know, when he's old?
Like, this is what my dad did, right?
And how do, how do we get to the point where we're so deep in that sort of servitude that you understand that self development is how you do that, right?
So, so this is how you incorporate self into it is because if I don't go, if, uh, I don't go kill the dragons when he's out in war, what advice do I have to give?
Right?
So I try to tell myself those three things.
My daughter, my son.
And then also the last thing, how do you get through hard situations?
And this is for parents.
Live the advice you want to give them, right?
So I'm gonna go to jet when he's 16 and tell him to nut up.
Like, when I'm sitting in the garage, which is where I sit, when I'm like, how is this gonna work?
Like, how are we gonna get out of this?
Like, right, not up.
Like, this is it.
This is a perfect opportunity for you to say one day, God, I remember when.
And this is why, okay?
And this is what I, I, I, uh, said this caption.
I feel like this perfectly kind of describes, um, what I'm saying.
The only thing I truly care about is that when you grow up and you have your own kids, that you think I was a man Worth modeling that you and your.
You.
That you, your siblings and your mom know that I gave everything I had in me, and every day would be a perfect day to die for you.
And, man, that's just it, bro.
Uh, like, that's nasty, Nate.
But he's developed, right?
Like, I.
Bro, when I tell you that I would have just had a smile on my face to die on the bike and.
And know that, like, the following weekend that my boys were gonna go run from the cops because I had passed the weekend before, I would have been so happy.
And I was just willing to lay down my life for that.
That season of my life.
And it's like, if I don't keep that, um, I'm missing the point of why that happened, right?
So it's like when people talk about trauma, right?
Or, like.
And I just.
I want to be careful with that because I.
I wanted previous podcasts, and I think it would be fantastic to watch these old podcasts that we did to see how far we've come, right?
And to see me talk about trauma and all this and all.
And this is so new age.
And again, I.
I'm here to.
You know, there's a hundred other 111 episodes.
If I piss you off, you can watch another one, right?
But my.
The.
What, uh, the rulebook that I believe in that has saved me from the depths of hell tells me that this is black and white and this is how this thing goes, okay?
And I just believe that there's so much depth here that we miss, right?
As far as, like, the test is supposed to be the testimony, right?
So it's like, I feel like we sh.
We.
We blame the trauma and, like, the thing so much that you fail to go, wow.
And again, here goes the representation, Jake, that I was talking about.
A, ah, team to represent.
I.
That happened to me, so I fixed it so it doesn't happen to others.
What other cause do you need to fight for?
Right?
And now we're talking about men's, um, mental health, right?
And again, we have talked about this in previous episodes where I would be embarrassed for somebody to watch that.
Not understanding that happiness is not the aim.
Fulfillment is the aim.
What does fulfillment mean?
This is worth it.
Okay?
Am I happy all the time raising my three children, uh, homeschooling them, doing all the hard stuff?
No, I'm absolutely not happy.
But then when I watch my son operate in a public setting and kids are doing stuff and he's doing something else, I sure am like, wow, this is worth it, bro.
You can't buy that, dude.
You, you can't like pay, pay a subscription price for that feeling.
That's, that's not, you know, falling in love and working hard for something you're proud of has nothing to do with busting a nut, dude.
It's like.
Exactly.
People get caught up in trying to like thinking that, oh, if I'm just happy, if I just really get what I think I want, then I'll be fulfilled.
And then what about tomorrow?
Dude.
Yes.
You know, yeah, sorry, interrupt gone.
No, and I love that you said that.
So again, the idea is like, um, you know, and this is so.
And I've done so much work on.
What are the parts of, you know, the four year.
What are the parts of the four year old podcast that.
Or, uh, the five year old podcast that are valuable, right?
That need to go.
Okay, you need to work on the things that he was talking about.
So whatever, Five years ago, that podcast that we were talking about, there's the battles and there's the boys that are now your audience, right?
That need this way, that need this, that need this wisdom.
You know what I'm saying?
So, um, yeah, I just, you know, and you know, jumping off from there, just what we talked about before in the last episode, just like, you know, always trying to like, you know, seek this like, happiness and, you know, ah, you know, everything's are so hard.
It's like, yeah, that's how it is and that's how it's supposed to be, right?
My favorite scripture.
To whom much is given, much will be required, which is Spider Man.
Great power, great responsibility, right?
If you want what you say you want, expect it to be difficult, right?
But again, scripture, bro, I mean, this book there is.
I'm, um, as, uh, I'm sitting with it right here.
There's nothing, there's nothing wrong in here, right?
So, um, that's where wisdom is created, is in difficulty, right?
And we know this, but this is like all these things and even Jake, us going back to the people that we were talking about before, Bob Proctor, you know, Neville Godard, all these people.
Guess what?
These guys were quoting Scripture, bro.
These guys were quoting scripture.
Um, who's, who's the super, super old Neville Godard and, um, uh, bro, they were quoting.
They were quoting scripture.
I didn't realize that until I was like listening to them, right?
Thinking like, oh, these guys are the, these are the guys, right?
Right?
Because like, oh, I'm not listening to the, the new guys.
I'm listening to the OGs and I'm like, but they were listening to the OGs, which is the disciples, right?
Um, even, um, Napoleon, uh, Hill, and he was quoting scripture.
I'm like, bro, these guys that we believe are like the.
These are the oat and then the people that are ripping their material, right?
Because we're all.
Nothing is created nor destroyed, right?
We can all agree with that.
All these ideas are already floating.
It's our life experience that brings out the new perspective which now new ears can hear.
New ears can hear.
Yeah.
But the thing is, we would have never accessed the scripture in the way that you read it now.
You wouldn't have had access to it meaning much to you if it was inputted to.
If it was handed in the same way it is to you now.
Meaning, um, the way that those people that we learned from, the way that they heard it and interpret it and ran it through their own experiences and their own experience of being a man and gave it to us, that was enough for us to go, that's interesting.
I like that.
And then, sure enough, five, six years later, you're like, oh, I'm, like, jumping ahead.
I'm reading the books that he read.
Uh, and then I'm finding out who the author that is and reading that book.
Yeah, it's.
Yeah.
So it's.
So that.
That metaphor right there is exactly what I believe that it is to be men and to be and to go.
Again, there's another scripture.
Um, it doesn't.
It doesn't relate to death, but it's the, um.
The servant of the talents.
Um, guys are asked to hold.
Hold money, you know, gold, whatever, and they're asked to invest it.
And then when they bring back more, the.
The.
You know, the king says, um, well done, my good and faithful servant.
And I just see that as such a great.
And this has, uh, again, nothing to do with death, but such a great thing to hear before your time here is.
Is.
Is gone.
Right?
Like, well done, my good and faithful servant.
Like, you know, you.
You have.
And, uh, you have.
I have entrusted you with little, therefore I will give you much, is what it says.
But it's like, I feel.
It's like I've trusted you with.
With what you were supposed to do here, right?
And it's like, that's.
I feel like.
Like you said, we wouldn't have heard it if it wasn't from.
There is like, this line, like, don't be the guy in this life, in your lineage, in.
In.
In like, in your town, in your sphere, in your purpose.
Don't be the guy that gets out of line, right?
That you're asking to sign yourself up for misery and a life of just, like, chasing pleasure and all this kind of things.
When you exit, I call it like, um.
I love using war as metaphor because it's so barbaric, right?
Like, imagine you have a post to sit at, right?
This is your post.
Here's your gun.
Here's your thing, and this is your.
No one else can sit here.
This is.
I'm supposed to guard this door.
This is my shift, and no one else is coming.
Imagine you get up, right?
Like, that's how I look at it, with purpose.
And what we're supposed to do here is like.
Like you said, you know, you were, um.
We can be the next guys in the line that find the information that saved us from, you know, kind of both where we were.
We're like, bro, I just want to cash this in.
Like, I kind of just want to be done here.
But guess what, Jake?
I realize it's all been the same mentality, bro.
This is how close anybody that's in misery.
You are so close to being right where you're supposed to be, because the mentality never changed.
I would rather do this than be here.
Okay?
I take that same thing, and I just.
Jake, I remember this, bro.
I remember being like, bro, uh, just.
Just do it, bro.
Just do it.
Because I would say I would rather die than experience what I'm experiencing right now.
And I say the same thing all the time.
If I don't squeeze the juice out of me, right?
The potential that I feel like I'm, um.
Uh, that is there.
I'd rather just cash it in.
And I know that I won't cash it in.
So with that being said, anything short of squeezing a juice is like death.
Um, so that's, um.
What gives me the gusto is like, this is life or death.
And how did I come about this?
Scripture, bro?
Scripture is very black and white.
There's no gray area.
And I feel like the people that really, just really live.
Live life, bro.
It's very like, I'm doing this or nothing, right?
Or I'm doing this or this.
It's not like, well, maybe do this, and I'll grab a little bit of that here, and I'll take a little bit of this, and, yeah, throw some of that on top.
It's like, no.
It's like, we're going for this life, and that's it.
I tell my wife it's either Ferrari or food stamps.
I'm going to own the island or I'm going to sleep on it.
That's it.
There's no in between.
I.
I think there's a power that comes up.
I think about this often.
I try to find ways to elegantly write about it because, um, you know, I've been in kind of like the, the mental health.
Uh, I just got my mindfulness meditation teacher certification and stuff.
So a lot of my writing, I try to write about suicide in a way that's not cringy or weird or like, overly, uh, like, be careful everyone.
I'm m about to talk about suicide.
Like, there's part of that that feels like shitty.
Um, but, uh, I think something that I keep coming to that was you.
So useful for me, like back in the day when we were going through those sorts of things is dude.
And I heard somebody else say it on a podcast and it clicked with me because I made the decision myself.
If you remove the option of suicide, like, if you just commit in this lifetime, if you do one thing and you say, I will under no circumstance ever take my life, no matter how hard it gets, no matter how painful it gets, I will not ever give up my life.
That option is now off the table, dude.
So now, now what are you going to do when it gets hard?
That option of like, you know what, maybe you start that self wallowing.
And I'm not trying to make anybody who experiences that feel.
I've been there, Nate's been there.
But I think removing it as it's.
It is not an option.
It's suddenly like it forces you to, to look up and like, maybe, maybe there's not a magical staircase of light that lights up, but maybe there's like a speck of light in the dark and it's 20 miles away, but like, it's something.
And you're like, I know I can't go back because I made the commitment that I can never go into darkness.
Start walking towards that light.
And sure enough, I think what's really hard about that, bro, is tell us when we were there, the things I'm about to say.
Right?
Yeah.
You, ah, don't know.
Just like for me, dude, my life.
You don't know, dude.
You couldn't even fathom the things I've been.
You couldn't.
You have no idea.
Right?
So, so how do we reach that guy?
I try to do my best.
Because the best part about this, bro, is I love Peter, bro.
In the Bible, because Peter was.
Peter was a dog, bro.
Like, Peter had a business.
Peter was doing all this stuff.
And Peter was also breaking the rules, right?
Peter was, Peter was working on Sunday.
Peter wasn't supposed to be working on Sunday.
Right.
Peter, um, was kind of.
I just, I, Peter was supposed to preach the gospel.
He was just this super passionate guy.
And I just, I, I, I love that because I can say I do this thing where I heard 50 Cent do it, and I'd start doing it ever since.
He says, when I'm in trouble, I'm 50 Cent.
When I'm not, I'm Curtis Jackson.
Okay?
So the best part about this is I can talk about this, but I'm a, But I'm a stunt writer, right?
I'm not a preacher.
So what does that mean?
I'll follow the same rules that these guys have to follow, because I don't get up on Sunday and stand in front of a camera and, and get in the, the pulpit, because that's a responsibility I'm not ready for.
But the cool part about this is I can share my experiences, but I'm still a stunt rider.
So if I mess it up or if I say something I'm not supposed to say, right?
Um, when I realized K.
And this is, and, and for man, I hope, and I hope we serve people in this moment.
That's what I pray that, I pray that anybody that's.
It's in this, in this phase right now.
I hope that we, I hope that serve them as.
I have this gun underneath my seat, right?
Ooh.
This is, this is what I needed to hear that I wasn't ready to receive.
So if you're not ready to receive it, I apologize.
But this is, you know, this.
Here goes my testimony.
Um, the weight that you feel that makes you want to end the game is purpose and responsibility.
Okay?
So.
And behind that is, Think about it.
If you want to end your life, you feel powerless, you feel hopeless, right?
You imagine you don't know how to ride a bull and somebody straps you to it and you can't fall off.
Imagine that, okay?
That's how you feel in the most violent way, right?
Your teeth are getting acted against the horns like, and I mean death.
We're talking about death, right?
So imagine that it's getting stuck through your face like that, that type of weakness, um, and just out of control.
And I know now, again, hindsight's 20 20, that that responsibility and that wake that I felt was purpose and, and just, like, I don't want to say taking control, but, like, answering the call, right?
And I felt like I was so weak.
Check this out.
And again, when you're in this space you're already in.
You're.
You're doing everything wrong, right?
So you're so weak, mate, to not take this responsibility that you can't even kill yourself.
You don't have the balls.
You can't even get this right.
You can't even commit to this.
You're not committing to anything.
You can't even.
You want this quote, unquote, but you won't even commit to that, otherwise it'd already be done, right?
So again, same type of mentality like I talked about throughout the years, pointed in the wrong direction.
Okay, so we're showing here lack of commitment to life, lack of commitment to purpose, but also lack of commitment to decision.
You're not Nate.
Make the decision, then let's get it done.
Right?
So.
But how hard is that to hear in that moment?
Like, I'll never forget I have a friend who, you know, Jay Cotterell, right?
And I'm doing this, and I'm drinking and I'm smoking, and I'm showing up drunk, driving at, uh, his house.
And, you know, halfway, you know, hanging out the door, I'm gonna kill myself.
You're like, do it.
You won't.
And if you do, I won't be at your funeral.
And, man, that just hit me like a ton of bricks, bro.
Just like.
He's right.
Like, I won't.
Right?
So what is this cry for help?
Right, so.
And we can get so deep into this, right?
Um, the.
The lack of.
I didn't lack, you know, fatherhood, but just, like, who was.
There's a book.
Anybody that's.
It's into scripture or just wants to explore spirituality while the heart.
It's a book on spiritual masculinity.
References the Bible.
His, uh, name's John Eldridge.
He uses a.
A, uh, term, and he says, who.
Who will give the man his name?
Right?
And he says, the father gives the man his name.
What does that mean?
This.
This last name that you wear on your back, this is what we represent.
What's that word?
Represent?
Like I talked about before, something to represent.
This is what we do.
This is how we handle.
This is how when things get tough, this is where you go, right?
You.
You come to the house.
We do this.
We have this.
We, you know, we go.
So there's no.
What's.
The coping mechanisms?
There is none in place, right?
It's just.
This is hard exit.
But where does this Come from, right?
Lack of structure within coming from.
Ideally, we'd get it from our fathers, right?
So this is why the same thing from the bike down to the suicide.
I would rather this.
I would rather die than this, right?
So for me, I would rather die than not feel like I gave my son enough.
And of course he's going to go through his own, right?
But my job is to.
Hey, you're four for the next 16 years before you have to stick this sword in this dragon's neck.
We're going to sharpen it every day, bro.
We're going to sharpen it every day.
So when you go to stick in this neck, it goes all the way through, bro.
And you don't have no problems, right?
So that is the harsher version of it.
The more light version, I would say, is like, imagine there's a book that's written about your life, and it's.
It's already done and it's already written, okay?
So if.
When this book says, even at the very beginning, I carefully knitted you in your mother's womb and I knew you beforehand, okay?
So if I have a place here, okay, it's just very simple, right?
I'm not.
Again, I'm not a preacher, okay?
This is what I read.
Here we go.
This is what helps me.
If I have a place here and these things are already done.
Scripture says if I do this, then this happens.
If I do this, and this is a good life, if I do, right?
It's already.
Why, uh, do I need to go?
Like, my purpose is already chosen for me at least.
But again, we have this idea that we think we know this kind of stuff, right, Jake?
Like, I know I got purpose here and, and all this, but I really gotta find it and I really gotta do it, and I really gotta make a lot of money and I really gotta make sure I'm successful and all this kind of stuff.
But it's like.
But you keep leaning on yourself.
It's already done, right?
If it's already planned, okay?
And.
And I'm gonna.
I have one more thing after this to land the plane, okay?
If it's already done, just step into it, right?
So again, there Nate was, same mentality.
He's going down there, all he has to do is turn.
I don't have to change at all.
Nothing about me.
I'm, um, still a dog, bro.
I still barely sleep.
I still train like a professional athlete.
I haven't rode in two years.
Nothing about me has changed.
I'd still rather die than this.
Nothing has changed, okay?
Just step into it.
Answer the call.
The, the call, the call happens every single day.
All you have to do is answer it.
That is the weight that we're feeling is that we feel like men are designed to have a place here, right?
We're designed to be inspirational, quote unquote.
That's why we look at all these other guys.
Why do we get jealous?
If you didn't believe that you were supposed to be like that, you wouldn't get jealous, okay?
So imagine things are already planned out and all you have to do is, is step into it, okay?
And for anybody that, that is thinks I'm cuckoo, totally fine.
All I ask is what?
Can we argue that if you followed the ten Commandments, which is are just the general rules, you could argue that you could live a better life.
That's all I'm going to say.
Okay, we can argue that, right?
You know, you're not going to steal, you're not going to kill, you're not going to commit adultery, do all these things.
Very basic.
Um, you could have a better life and imagine you get all the way to the end and you find out it's not true.
Let's just say that, okay?
We find out this is all bullshit, okay?
You can look back and be like, well, shit, at least I live a good life while I was here, right?
At least I was good to other people, right?
Treat your neighbor as yourself.
But here's the nightmare.
Imagine you get all the way to the end and you find out and you didn't follow the rules, right?
Or you just, like, did whatever you want to do and you were just wild and you were just out doing girls and doing all this stuff and, you know, sleeping with people's wives like I was and all this.
And then you get to the end and you find out, oh, this was real.
Oh, my God.
Like, look where I'm headed.
Not only look where I'm headed, but look at all of the heads, right?
Look at this, like, metaphorically that I've taken and people's lives that I've ruined, bro, if somebody, if some, if another man slept with my wife, bro, I, I, I don't know what I would do, bro.
Like, I, I, I truly don't know if I could stomach that, right?
It was like just a, like I was there, just like, oh, no, no, no problem.
Like, yeah, no, don't worries, don't worry about it.
Yeah, you're not here.
Like, so that is just like, and, and the reason I'm, um, I know I'm ranting, but I just want to, I just want to give credit where credit is due, right?
Because people are going to look on these old pods and wow, I remember that guy.
Whatever.
Yeah, whatever.
And it's like, here's a new version of him, you know?
Yeah, yeah, absolutely.
I mean, I think not, uh, that the place where you and I both were at in those podcasts was still a great spot, especially for a couple gents at that age.
And especially for, um, you know, just for both of us, for, you know, the past that we had before.
So we were just kind of going through things out loud in a lot of ways.
Um, and now I love the perspective that you're at.
I love like where you've arrived.
It's.
It's so beautiful, dude.
It's like, I feel like everything is trying to tell us in some way.
Stop thinking about yourself and serve other people.
Like server you can reach.
And you hear it and you hear it and you hear it.
And then like, you think about it.
Yeah, yeah, it's.
And the, and the, the thing that, I mean, you know, is that we can all agree most of the time that it feels good.
Why is it that our brain is wired for that?
Again, like, oh, let's think about coincidence, you know what I mean?
Like, and also too men, okay?
It's a pride thing, okay?
We have this like, again, these beautiful, beautiful, beautiful traits built into us that we go this way with, okay?
When I show up, right?
And if I have, I mean, bro, I went, I'm, I'm willing to wear.
I would, I, I'm more willing, right?
Let's just say I was in a bad situation.
I'm more willing to wear rags to have my wife and kids dress nicely, right?
All day.
Yeah, I, I am far more prideful and going, yo, I'm taking, I'm taking care of that, right?
Like, but you think about it, Think about what I just said.
Yeah, I'm taking care of that.
And think about.
But then the self serving ego at uh, in, in that saying that same sentence, right?
Like, yeah, look at my car.
I'm taking care of that.
Yeah, look at my car.
Like, look at my, look at my, look at my money.
Look at my this, look at my that.
Look at my watch.
Like, look at all this, right?
And think of how much more depth that's there when you're really.
Again, because it's like that same mentality.
I'm not gonna prom.
You're not gonna die for a watch, bro.
The difference is when I say I'm taking care of my.
I'm, um, I'll die for this right here, right now, right?
Like if somebody comes and there's a situation, um, I'm, um, no problem taking a bullet.
When someone comes and like, give me your watch, you're gonna be like, bet.
Here, take it.
Right?
Like, no problem.
Yeah, yeah, absolutely, bro.
You want that?
Here, let me give you this too.
It's like, what, what are you assigning value to?
Exactly.
So, Jake, I'm.
I'm really in a place, bro, where I'm trying to take.
And this is perfect, bro.
We're building my bio for the front.
I'm, um, really trying to build the exact life that I want based upon this story that I've always told.
As everyone's seen on my Instagram, the underdog, right?
The guy that never quits, the guy that rolls around in the concrete and never made a single dollar from it, never had a back up and get him right back on.
I'm trying to build that narrative by building the exact life I want by following these rules.
And then when I get there saying that these the rules I followed, I feel like that's a pretty simple way to put it, right?
He's like, well, you know, why do you believe that?
Well, this says it right here, bro.
This is why I believe.
Well, like, and you could also, like, you now realize you could make the most legitimate impact that way.
When it's not so much like, I'm not trying to like, you know, there's this ego side of like, dude, do what I do.
Did.
You're just like me.
I see myself in you.
And, you know, there's helpful ways into connecting with people with that.
But 101 thing I love about any sort of spirituality is not like, um, like, let, let me bite.
Size this for you in packages for you, interpret it for you.
It's like, no, hey, man, this, this scripture, this book worked for me.
Just give it a read.
Read this.
Yeah, like, hey, check this out again.
It's not again, Right?
The argument, the argument that I always make is, can we argue that if you follow these rules, you would probably live a better life, Right?
Even if you wanted to use it selfishly, if you read this stuff as affirmations, you would believe in yourself more.
Yeah.
Do you see a man competent in his work?
He will serve before kings.
Can we not say that's a great affirmation to read?
How do you.
How do you get to the people?
And I wonder if your answer has changed, like, what you would have Said a couple years back.
A lot of times people even having these conversations, are participating in these conversations.
I mean, you probably notice it in your everyday life.
I mean, really, anybody who is.
Has like, Christian conversations in public, spiritual conversations in public.
If there's somebody who, like, they consider themselves an atheist or like, God isn't their thing, like, they cannot even.
Like, it just seems so foreign, what you're talking.
They can't contribute.
It makes them uncomfortable.
Um, what is your.
I like to try to speak to people like, hey, you think that this is something that only spiritual people talk about?
You think that, like, the things we're talking about, the mental quarrels, only has to do with, like, the Bible and what Jesus did?
It's like, no, this stuff is a, ah, diagram.
It's a blueprint for a human experience.
And it saddens me.
I wonder how you think about it or like, maybe how you would talk to them in these days.
It saddens me when people are like, dude, keep that shit away from me.
And then they're still suffering.
They're still going antidepressants.
They're still.
Exactly.
Jesus will solve all your problems.
That's not what I'm trying to say.
This isn't just for religious.
Yeah.
And I want to be open and transparent.
Saying, Jesus won't solve all your problems.
That's.
That's a great way to start.
Yeah, is.
No, absolutely, bro.
I.
Here's the thing.
This is.
Oh, uh, this is what I love about this, bro, is I know people, and this is not a holier than thou statement.
Right?
Like, I'm not.
Oh, I'm better.
I know people that have been in the church for 10, 15 years longer than me.
And the fruit that I see is.
Is.
Is so much sweeter because I believe so much more because I met God in the trenches.
They met God because their parents told them to.
Okay?
That's why I'm so passionate about this.
Because when there was no one left, nothing left, and I was about to end it all, that's when this thing happens and it, like the light kicks on or something, right?
It's like the.
The.
And again, there it is, Jake.
The same mentality.
If I don't.
I'm the.
I'm, um.
The guy.
Used to be the guy.
Okay, Are we drinking?
All right, cool.
Well, let's block out this time because I'm gonna black out.
Right?
Like, oh, no, no, no, no.
We're just coming out for drinks.
All right, cool.
Call me when you guys are done.
We get back to the house because I'll be passed out.
Right?
The mentality has always been the same.
I've always been extreme.
And that is the best part about it, is because I don't feel like you can properly squeeze the juice out of something unless you are extreme.
So with that being said, the people that.
And this is not a direct answer to your question, but I'm trying to lay the foundation.
The people that are very like, oh, I don't believe in anything.
That's totally fine.
And again, I don't.
I truly don't care what people believe.
I'm not trying to force you to convert anybody either.
No, no, but like.
But like, if you don't believe in anything, no kidding, you haven't exhausted anything yet.
Go to the other side.
I challenge you.
Go there.
Go to the dark side.
See how you like it.
Go there first.
That's where I went.
Right?
But it's like when you're in the middle, nothing you.
You can't believe because nothing has happened to make you believe.
Imagine you met the devil at his feet.
You're going to believe now.
You see what I'm saying?
So that's why I just always tell people, whatever that is there, explore that thing.
Very, very harsh reality.
I was in, like, a men's group of these guys, and they were talking about.
And we talked about this before, kind of like dabbling in porn, right?
And it's like, you know.
Yeah, it's just not that big of a deal.
It's only a couple times a week.
I'm like, watch it for eight hours a day.
You don't want to kick the.
You don't want to kick the habit because you.
Your whole life.
And again, this is like.
This is where I'm gonna sound like I'm trying not to, but this is where that, like, in the locker room talk comes in, right?
And.
And it's like, I'm not.
I'm not a.
I'm a stunt writer, right?
I'm not a preacher.
I'm a stunt writer.
But I'm also.
I'm, um.
This is what got me here, right?
This is what got me good on the bike.
This is what got me, you know, in the business and all these things is you're dabbling everywhere, right?
You're.
You dabble in the diet.
That's why you're overweight.
You dabble in the gym.
That's why you're out of shape.
You're dabble in your marriage.
That's why your wife's unhappy you dabble with your kids because that's why they don't listen to you.
And it's not they have to listen, but they.
They listen when they respect you.
Right.
The kids don't listen to you.
Every.
Everything's half ass.
So of course you don't need to kick this habit because you're half assing this too.
I didn't half ass it because I was watching porn all the time on the max on the way home from.
From Nike.
Like, uh, my job, literally.
Oh.
Just not even doing.
Just watching it just for entertainment.
That's crazy, by the way.
That's insane.
Fully submerged in it.
But I only believe now in the light because I was fully submerged in the darkness.
But I had to go there.
Not to anchor us, just on the porn fact.
But you don't watch porn now, right?
Absolutely not.
No, bro, if I'm not.
If.
If I'm m.
Not, bro.
I mean, I'm fully.
Um.
Even times when my wife and I are still having sex, I still practice semen retention.
Yeah.
Well, so I want to point it out just because I'm sure there's tons of people.
If somebody's listening right now, when they are the person who's on the Metro watching porn, they can't get enough of it.
I mean, dude, how many posts on Reddit do you see nowadays of kids just like, I can't stop watching porn.
Help.
Yeah.
And so I wouldn't say that the poll was like that.
Like it was an addiction.
I.
I would 100 because I was with so many partners at that time that the pull to watch it on my screen was not an addiction, but it was just like, sex is my life kind of.
You know, I mean, it was like, well, yeah, like right after this, I'm going home to meet somebody and then later meet somebody else.
And it's like, it was just so, like, it was just like, um, it was just like our caffeine, right?
It's like, no.
Do I need to get it right this second?
No, but like, yeah, we're going to the gas station in a half hour.
You know what I mean?
So it wasn't like I had this.
Like, I wasn't addicted to porn, but sex was a huge part of my life, so it was like, oh, well, yeah, sex is happening, so let's watch it.
You know?
I mean.
Yeah, Yeah, I get you.
Well, so I.
I think I try to see it nowadays kind of as.
Like a.
I know, I realize it didn't answer your question, but kind of what I would like to say within that before was like, explore one of the two, right?
Because the more you stay in the middle.
And we know this, Jake, right?
It's like the cold plunge thing.
It's like, if you put one foot in, you never really get in, you know, get in the damn thing.
Okay?
So if you don't want to come here, check out the other side first.
See what they have to offer, right?
It's like one of those things where it's like, you're an employer.
You're like, hey, you think.
You think the grass is greener?
Go ahead and check it out.
When you come back, we'll be here waiting for you.
Right?
That's kind of, uh, how I like to put it because, again, it makes me very, like, I don't want to push this thing on you, but I know what it's like to be there.
And also, too, for anyone listening, I don't want to.
I don't really push a religion, so it's like, I push having a relationship with.
Reading this, like, what does this mean to you when you.
When it hits your brain and when it hits your head and when it hits your lips?
Like, what does it mean to your life when it comes out?
Not like, you need to be Christian, you need to be Catholic, you need to be Muslim, you need to be this.
This.
Like, I don't subscribe to that, right?
I go to a Christian church.
But I don't say, like, you need Christianity in your life.
Like, I don't.
I'm not that guy, right?
So I'm the guy that's like, read this book and whatever comes good out of here for you that you can take to benefit your life, because I get 110% say that your life will change for the better.
See what happens?
Well, and it's kind of fascinating, like, the way that the scriptures are interpreted.
Interpreted, uh, at different points in our lives.
Like, so they might stumble upon scripture that right now is profound to them.
And then they read it five years.
It's like.
It's also profound, but it means something completely different.
It's somehow with that stuff, there is a weird synchronistic nature of when you hear things.
It kind of, like, wiggles its way around obstacles inside you and, like, penetrates where it's supposed to and gives you a little bit of hope to continue on.
And that's how, like, I feel like all wisdom has been, right?
You're like.
It's like you read a book for the second time, and it was different.
Than you read it the first time.
You know what I mean?
I feel like, same kind of idea.
So, yeah, I feel like that's the only way I feel, like, to answer your question without, uh, like, you know, coming up people's necks, you know, I mean, it's like, yo, just try.
Because at this point, I feel like the people that are that waffle again, they're waffling everywhere, right?
It's like the same idea.
Like the whole men's group thing.
We're talking about kind of like drinking, um, you know, and for.
For me, like, I haven't had a drop in alcohol and like, I think almost nine years.
I'm, um, going on nine years.
No, no, like, no sips, no like, oh, this and that.
No.
No nothing.
Um, and I, um.
I just.
I say.
I'm like, just do it.
That's what we're called to do, right?
Like, imagine 50 years ago, 60 years ago, or whatever.
And I'm not a history.
Not okay.
I'm a stunt writer.
Um, these kids were lying about their age to storm on the beaches, knowing their fate was to get shot in the head.
Like, that is the type of passion that we all carried not that long ago.
And now it's like, we're just dull, right?
Right?
Like, everything is just dull.
And we're constantly being diminished by this on a daily basis, right?
And you're just.
You're just pouring garbage into again.
What we're supposed to believe is the only true thing that matters here, right?
Like, on this earth, this is the most important thing that you possess.
And you dump.
You fill it with garbage every single day.
Not only do you fill with garbage, you're supposed to move it.
You don't.
You're supposed to feel it.
Right?
Like, all these things.
And I just feel like passion is the thing that people are like, God, this guy's nuts.
Me, right?
And it's like, that's what you're missing, right?
Like, the people that.
Again, I've always dealt with this criticism of, like, you're so extreme, right?
Like, the food, the this, the that, and it's like, it's actually passion, right?
Wouldn't it be awesome for you and your life?
How much would your life change if you believed in something as much as I do?
Right?
Like, even food, bro, I get.
I get.
I will talk like this.
And how we're having this conversation about steak.
Like, imagine all, uh, how, like, how much.
How much would this experience change for you if you were that passionate about everything that you thought about that you loved and that you did, right?
Now we can.
Now we're just like getting into the worldly stuff.
Like, imagine how your everyday life would change if you're just so passionate about everything, right?
That's what's changed my life.
I knew that a job was not for me, right?
The traditional way that I was doing it, right.
I was a bartender that didn't drink.
I'm sitting here saying, I don't represent this.
I don't believe in this.
But here you go, pal, right?
Same idea.
I'm so passionate about this that I'm not.
I'd rather be broke.
Here's a financial death.
Here we go.
Same mentality.
I'd rather be broke than do this, right?
So.
But what's the underlying part of it is finding the juice, bro.
Finding the gusto, letting the dog out, right?
Like, that's what I feel like I'm trying to represent.
Is that everything that I believe to be true about this life or about how to live a good life or what I believe life's supposed to be, that people looked at me and be like, dude, that guy's a dog off the leash, bro.
That's what I want to represent, you know?
You know what I think you did?
Um, you know, being.
Being a, you know, a self certified intense person.
Let's say, you know, you're an extreme person.
I.
Intense is a word I use for myself.
That's kind of the same thing.
Intense.
Yeah, but.
And there's nothing wrong with it.
But.
So I.
I think what can happen is when we notice we are that sometimes we want to lessen ourselves or we want to kind of like put a shade or a blanket over our shining.
And sometimes I'm going to relate this to chakras.
I know.
I hope this isn't too big of a jump for people, but like, when you're just thinking about busting a nut, eating the best, you know, most delicious taste bud, appealing food, whatever.
Like, you see, you know, everybody knows a basic level of chakras.
You got your different colors, so you got seven of them.
And each one, you know, is, you know, your thoughts of the future, your ability to speak the truth, you know, your confidence is somewhere down here.
Whatever.
I think a lot of times extreme people, when they're denying their purpose, when they're trying to shut up, uh, God's invitation to be as big as they should be, as expansive as they're capable of being, we kind of shove and keep that energy inside.
And I think sometimes it gets shoved into chakras of sexual pleasure, of, um, wanting to just feel comfort the second we get hungry.
We don't like that because it's trying to get us out of our comfort zone.
So we just keep eating, you know, um, we just get shoved into our lower, like, monkey mind chakras, and we have all this energy.
Energy that's trying to go up to the other chakras and express itself and, like, change the world around us.
Like, change physical reality through our action, you know, Facts.
But it's being just squeezed down here.
And nowadays we got our magic rectangle, you know, and this thing is really good for keeping that energy, right?
It's a.
It's a black hole, right?
And a great thing to.
What you said, um, Victor Frankel, he.
What's he say?
A man who lacks purpose will seek pleasure.
Pleasure, comfort.
Okay.
Um, let's just go to, like, worldly success, right?
Let's argue the idea of, like, the, you know, the intensity and, like, the guru, right?
What do they say?
Like, you got to do this, you got to do that.
There's no other option.
Like, all these, like, motivational speeches.
Scripture literally says, right?
So this is why I argue for the extremism, the passion, the intensity, bro.
Scripture literally says, if your eye cause you to sin, gouge it out, right?
So it's like, think.
Remember, like what.
What we used to do.
Like, you know, we gotta cut the dead weight.
Like, you know, like, whatever's holding us back, it's gotta go.
Friends, family, everything's gotta go, right?
The food's gotta go.
Like, the thing's got to go.
You know what I mean?
Like.
But it's like, it's.
Do you see the alignment there?
You know what I mean?
Like, uh, when you.
When you.
Bro.
And also, too.
When you're really in your lane and you're really in your bag, this just comes natural.
You just start ignoring stuff on accident, you know what I mean?
You stop seeing things on, like, on accident, for instance, right?
I believe people say the most important thing in this life is time.
We can argue that.
I'd say it's perspective.
And what do I mean by that?
How two people can sit in the same exact room and experience two different things.
The time is ticking, right?
But the perspective may never change, right?
So imagine, like, you're like, oh, my gosh, I really got 80 years here.
This is crazy.
And the other person's like, man, uh.
Oh, my God, my 80 years is just, like, diminishing as we speak.
You know what I mean?
Who's going to live a different life, right?
Or, for instance, you know, I'm sitting in the car with my dad the other day, and, um, I was like, did you see that guy looking at me like, you know, whatever?
And I'm like, I'm like.
Or like, you know, that guy's got a problem.
And I'm like, I didn't even see him.
Like, which guy?
Dude?
Like, this happens to me all the time.
So the.
So the glasses, right?
The lenses in which you see things.
The most powerful thing that you can grasp onto in this life.
And then with that, let's be passionate about what lens you're putting on.
Bro, wouldn't you.
Again, would.
Can't we just say that if you just woke up and you were as passionate about waiting until 2pm to eat a steak as me, like, bro, I'm so juiced to wait all day and then have it.
I'm like, but this is the.
This is the act of gratitude, which is the actual key to raising the vibe, right?
Like, the highest form of energy is gratitude.
There is nothing in this moment that gets better than this.
Tell me if you can have as many of those moments as possible, even when there's pain, right?
Right.
Dude, my son, you know, having a huge meltdown, tantrum, doing all this stuff, right?
And it's just.
It's just, open the door.
He's not ready.
Open the door.
He's pounding on the door, all these things.
And we sit down and he breaks down and we're there and we're like, do you like having this?
It's like, there is nothing in this moment that is better than this, right?
So how many of those moments can you collect?
But, uh, what I see is.
And again, broadening out the metaphor to, like, even worldly success, right?
And I want to kind of connect world and spiritual is how often do we get to that pain?
The tantrum, right?
The metaphorical tantrum.
Close the door.
Let him cry it out.
See, in an hour we do that with the other things that we work on, right?
Close the door.
Whatever.
I'll get on my phone.
It can happen tomorrow, it can happen this day, it can happen that day.
Whatever.
I'll put it off, I'll put it off, I'll put it off.
And then we're lacking those moments of right now.
Nothing is better than this because we have yet to, like, go through the fight that gets there.
And this is where I'm talking about how in the difficulty is where the winning actually happens.
And that's where it is.
And so, um, again, Scripture said, you will rejoice in your suffering, right?
So I just.
But the.
But the key to it is that it has to be seen through.
So all these moments, like, bro, imagine the.
The people that look back and they go that.
And, you know, like, marriage, they look all the way down their life and they look back on everything they created, and we're like, damn, Remember those times we almost threw in the towel?
Like, and here's all our grandkids, um, and we almost threw in the towel.
We almost quit.
There is nothing in this moment that is better than this, right?
So I think that the biggest thing that has changed since we did the last podcast, and I feel like that's the subject we're on, is, like, almost like evolution, right?
Is my perspective on life has just immensely shifted, right?
Um, and that is through and only through massive, massive, massive trial.
Massive, right?
Um, I like to tell a story because I like to, again, give credit where credit is due.
I quit my job like we were talking about before.
Um, I was miserable, right?
And I have the.
The.
The receipts to back it up.
Um, that ever.
I was just miserable.
I was just like, again, Jake, I'm right here, bro.
I am cleaning.
Um, I'm doing stain removal in car seats.
I'm doing stain removal, um, in.
In, uh, these dealerships.
And I look at myself and I say, if this is all that is in the plan, I'd rather die.
Same mentality, right?
Um, get into a fight with Clyde's dad.
Ah, Who I was working for.
Um, didn't go to work the next day.
I had $7 in my bank account, okay?
And I kept telling myself, you've done it your way for this long, right?
Let's try something else.
Okay?
So if I believe in.
And, uh, again, this is where the thing that I said, hey, maybe you don't believe, but let's just try, right?
Give this all you got and see what happens.
And.
And that's what it was.
I gave it all I had.
I don't have to believe myself.
I have to believe in what's already written, right?
I go to put gas in the car, I'm gonna put 10 bucks in.
Nope, fill it up.
You ain't got to believe in.
You believe in that, right?
Believe in what's already there.
Believe in that.
Believe in the words you read this morning, right?
So this is the same ideas, which are, um, New Age ways which I.
I was a part of, my wife was a part of, and no offense to anybody that's there at all.
Um, it just didn't work for me at all.
I was always seeking something else because it's like, oh yeah, who made these rocks?
Right?
Like, you know, how did this stuff get here, right?
Like, even the creator created the man who created this idea.
Like, you know what I mean?
So it's like, let me, let me go all the way to the end, right?
Let me be Nasty Nate, right?
Let me, let me see if I can jump over my handlebars at 70 on the highway when there's two cars next to me, right?
Let me do that with this, okay?
And so, um, mixing that with Nasty Nate birthed the life that I live now, which is I make my own money, I live by my own rules, I own my time.
If I don't want to do something, I don't have to, right?
I've also changed again my perspective of Jake.
That's the biggest thing is I've changed my perspective on I'm.
And this is where the scripture, I was just reading the scripture with.
Um, and if anybody's interested, um, I do have run a men's group on Sundays, Sunday mornings at 6:00am, uh, PST, Jake and Link that, um, and I was reading scripture with my guys last week and it says a, ah, Scripture says that you cannot serve two masters, right?
And this is where people get caught up in, you know, money's evil.
Money's evil.
No, money's not evil.
Money's uh, evil when it's your master.
Which means you change who you are as a man for it, right?
So if I'm gonna, and this is why I, I again, if you read these other books that say your giftful, you know, scriptures, your gift will make room for you.
It's already done, it's already written.
So if I think from that frame, right?
If I was.
And this is again like shifting from new age over to right here, people are like manifested, you know, affirmations.
It's, it's, it's bro, if I'm, I'm, I'm this guy regardless of what's going on, right?
So that changed so much for me that I actually, people don't understand is when I was broke, I was slave to money, right?
Like I didn't get out of $7 in my bank account and, and at that point, two dependents and a stay at home wife.
And I didn't get out of it to be financially independent.
Meaning I make my own money.
I'm not financially free.
Like, oh, I don't have to work Another day in my life.
But being financially independent, other than the fact that I said if I'm constantly thinking about this all the time and it's eating me up and I can't sleep because my account's negative.
Money's my master.
Mhm.
And imagine I'm master to something that another man is pressing a button and, and bringing to life.
This is where most Christians and most people in general get caught up in the, in, in being slave to money.
And again, I'm not saying that I don't have to work another day in my life.
But what I'm saying is, is I'm not going to let my life, which is my mood, my energy, the way that I operate, which I am the, the head to the rest of my family, I'm gonna be swayed and I'm gonna change my mood and change this and change that, and Dad's day's ruined, which means everybody else's day is ruined.
That's how it goes.
Because of a piece of paper.
Mhm.
But because of that perspective and mindset shift birth the business.
Otherwise that would have never happened.
I would have went back to what I was doing and being slave to the dollar.
I gotta have it right this second.
I need a paycheck now.
Right.
I.
I need to go.
They have it guaranteed for me.
Let.
Let me.
No, I was changing who I was.
Right.
What is your psychology with money now?
Like what?
Like how do you, like, uh, like right now, how do you think of money compared, uh, to how you used to think of money?
I think of it as a tool.
Right.
I think it of it as now is what are my priorities?
Okay.
My priority used to be money.
And crazy enough I didn't have a lot of it.
Right.
And I don't want to make lessons about money.
I want to talk about my limiting beliefs that kept me where I was.
That with.
I feel like what we're talking about is evolution that was birthed through me coming to scripture.
So which, which birthed worldly success for me.
Right.
Like I'm at where people.
Uh, you kind of see what I'm saying?
So I'm trying to follow the narrative of I'm evolving because I'm following this.
And here's uh, all the trials.
I had talked about suicide just so for anybody that's getting lost.
Right.
Talked about suicide, talked about like the, the mental health thing, talked about the bike.
Um, and now I feel like, uh, the last piece of it was like, okay, like if you think you're him.
Then, like, go make your own money.
You know what I mean?
Like, because, you know, you want that.
But again, it was another thing I wasn't committed.
Like, I'm doing gigs on the side here and there.
It's fine.
It's whatever.
And it's like, I don't expect also to full transparency.
I don't expect anybody to.
One, I'm not selling anything.
So, you know, I get a couple comments about that when I talk about money on my YouTube, um, on my YouTube videos.
We're like, oh, you sound like a guru.
And I'm like, dog, did you forget?
I don't have anything for sale.
This is for free.
You're welcome.
Yeah.
And for two, if anything, these are the people that always have this, like, minimal perspective.
I just told you, I 10x my income.
You should be happy for me if you're watching my video.
Oh, yeah, like, this.
This comment makes no sense, right?
Yeah, it's like, it really doesn't.
I'm like, bro, for one, I'm not selling anything.
For two, if you're.
If you watch the whole damn thing.
What I just said, you think I'm a guru, dog, you should be happy for me.
Like, what the hell?
Yeah, it's weird to be jealous of a stranger succeeding.
Crazy, bro.
And I just.
And I don't.
I'm not a successful person, right?
Like, I don't give credit to.
To, uh, I don't.
And this is not something I really even care about.
But I think the reason I talk about it is because it handcuffs so many people, right?
We're handcuffed to the dollar.
We're handcuffed to the currency.
We're handcuffed to the.
The rat race.
And it's like, you don't even actually have to do it.
No one says you have to.
And I think a big.
When I was first building my business.
Sorry, my relationship with money, it's a tool.
Um, I see it as time.
How now I'm not interested.
I used to be interested in stuff because that's what we see as success, right?
And this has been years.
Like, I think it would probably say, like, when I was 21, 22, I'm M.
Like, oh, yeah, I want this car.
I want that car.
I want this, I want that.
Until I realized that you can buy your time instead.
Right?
Yeah.
And that's.
And then now I realize, okay, if my son was the same age as my daughter.
And this is the.
The thing that always gets me.
It's always.
Nothing is more Important than this moment right now when I throw my daughter in the air and I'm just like doing it.
And you know how like for like when you have like a pencil or a pen you like and you go to pick up another one in that first moment, it's like, like this is weird.
Like right, I'll throw my daughter up in the air a couple minutes and I'll go to pick up Jet and it's like I go to use the same force and the same force doesn't bring the same height and his rib cage is wider and I'm like wow, like that was just you.
And so that, that can't be purchased.
What is more important than that?
So when people say you know, time, freedom, all this, all that, it is so again intense and extreme and passionate that I'm not even buying my time.
I'm buying the ability to be able to feel how wide my son's rib cage is today.
That's how deep the shit is to me.
Right.
And you cannot have this type of depth unless you have been so low that you appreciate the, that on that little, on that little of a level that when I do business and I personally think family men are the best men to do business with and this is why I take it so serious is because yeah, you're doing business with me, but you're putting food in my kids mouth.
So guess what?
I'm going to take care of you.
Right?
And not only am I going to take care of you, I'm going to take this business relationship serious.
Okay.
So go ahead bro.
I mean I, I just got excited.
I uh, I just think it's like if you consider money as energy as well, you know, I feel like I get to a point where I don't really want to be involved with the energy of dudes who are going to like someone else's wife.
Like I don't really want to do like even though it has nothing to do, like absolutely nothing to do with our transaction, if I know outside of has nothing to do with me that you are doing things that are.
It just starts to feel strange to me and maybe that stuff doesn't matter for everybody else, but I can't ignore when I feel it and I notice it, you know.
And so I find myself wanting to distance myself from, from those.
But um, yeah, I just think money, money has energy to uh, you know, accomplish and be present with where you're really at.
That's a.
Yeah, a ah, hundred percent, bro.
Yeah.
And I um, again just going along with like how I change my perspective.
Um, I had like a revelation where.
I mean, bro, things were bad, right?
Like, things were, were not doing.
I was not doing good financially.
I was having a hard time getting clients for video, all this kind of stuff.
And I remember the first month I made four grand, which was fifteen hundred dollars under what we needed for bills.
And, um, and this was like two or three years ago, I can't remember.
And I just remember my buddy saying that's how much money he makes a month.
And I'm like.
Even though I feel.
And this is where you need these moments, okay?
So, like anybody that's listening, think back on these moments where you can have these.
And this is why I feel like people waste this.
Right?
We talk about before we talk about trauma and all these things and how we're just wallowing it.
Oh, you don't use it, okay?
These moments are moments that need to be used and exhausted.
That for that four grand, I worked a day and a half, but I couldn't get any other work.
And for that four grand, my friend worked 20 days.
And in that moment I was like, you've already beat the game, bro.
Yeah, um, you've been losing.
You just have to.
But the.
But again, what it, what happens when you are in a low vibrational state?
You close yourself off to possibilities, right?
So what do you do?
Oh my God, I only made four grand.
I need fifteen hundred dollars more to pay my bills.
I don't know where I'm going to get it from.
I just, I'm, um.
A piece of my business doesn't work, nobody wants to pay me.
Right?
What am I doing?
I'm close.
Uh, I just was like, dog, I just made four grand a day and a half.
Well, what's I.
That means I can make, uh, uh, in three days, which is what I used to work six.
I can make 12 grand.
That means I'll make 12 grand a week.
Like, whoa, oh my.
I'm cooking now.
Right?
But it's like, you don't even think like that until you're out of that perspective and out of that state.
And scripture is what helped me change that.
Right.
A man, a man's gift will make room for him.
Like, okay, if I'm good at this, the clients are already there, right?
Like, can I ask you something?
What do you think about.
Ah, you can ask me whatever you want.
Uh, way too much, bro.
No, not at all, bro.
I did.
This is always how it is with you and I, man.
We always go on wonderful quests.
But Uh, I started from my potty mouth today too.
I didn't intend to have that, but.
No worries about it.
Um.
Um, okay, so.
So I was gonna ask something, and I've been wanting to explore this.
I've been kind of trying to write about it.
Um, but I think you'd be a good person to ask the whole, like, law of attraction manifestation, this whole world.
I mean, you've mentioned New Age a couple times.
It's, like, really prevalent in.
In that world.
And I noted, like, when I first stumbled into it, there was, like, years of it being so fun, so magic, so great, and I'm so glad I did it.
But then after a while, I noticed that I would get to this spot where I would.
I would go, uh, notice.
Oh, I'm thinking I'm, um, being negative.
I'm thinking about the.
Not the positive.
And then that itself would go, oh, oh, stop thinking about the bad stuff.
Oh, no.
And then you get in this, like, weird, like, where you basically start wallowing and end up sitting on the ground in defeat because you're like, I'm just being negative.
I've now just lost all my progress of positive thoughts, and I'm only attracting bad stuff to me.
Basically, you become afraid of your own mind.
Exactly.
How, uh, do you.
What's your thoughts on that?
How do we get out of that?
How do we not?
So, again, I'm not a preacher.
I'm a stunt rider, so I don't have full understanding of scripture.
But for what?
From what I understand, the enemy is defeated.
Foe.
Okay.
Which means that if you believe in the light, then the actually, like, the.
Not that the darkness doesn't exist, but it does not have power.
Okay.
So with that being said, like, my wife has experienced spiritual attacks.
She's had, um.
What is the thing where you're awake but you can't move?
What is that?
Um, like.
Like lucid dreaming when you wake?
Sleep paralysis, isn't it?
Sleep paralysis.
So she's had sleep paralysis before?
I believe so, yeah.
So she's had spiritual attacks before.
Um, and I have never experienced that ever.
Like, I don't feel like, you know, something's in a house or this or bad energy or whatever.
And.
And she was like, God, I wonder why?
And I was like, honestly, I don't believe in that.
I really don't.
I don't.
It doesn't cross my mind any way, shape or form that.
Do I believe that the enemy is a fallen angel?
Yeah.
Do I believe that there's people out here that are.
That are evil 100%.
But, like, do I believe that that has any effect on me whatsoever?
No, not at all.
So, um, I think it is belief, Jake, but I think it's the belief in the right thing, right?
So the way I look at it is.
And Christian men do this so much.
And this bugs the out of me, bro.
Bugs the shit out of me.
These guys give the enemy so much credit, bro.
Like, oh, the enemy's just really pulling me towards the porn.
The enemy's really attacking my financ finances.
And it's like, why does he deserve that credit?
Uh, unplug from that dude.
Yeah, it's just like, exactly.
So it's like.
And, uh, again, scripture says you cannot serve two masters.
So in that moment, you.
You're.
George Janko said this on a podcast one time.
He said, you're in that moment when you think like, I was just explaining you're serving the devil.
Is that something you want to do?
N.
Let me just change the channel, right?
So it's like.
It's all the same ideas, bro.
It just.
The credit has to just be given in the correct place.
And check this out again.
Why do most people, when they do this, manifesting affirmations.
Let me get to where I want to go.
Why is there always, like.
I do a lot of video stuff for guys in the day trading industry, and they're always changing cars, changing watches, changing this, changing that, new house, new this, new that.
What if that's not your grand purpose, my guy?
And that's why it's so fleeting.
And that's why no matter what you're driving, it doesn't m.
It doesn't change how you feel, because guess what?
You brought it upon yourself.
But one thing I do believe is that those powers do exist, right?
I believe in energy, okay?
I believe that all these things that we talk about do exist, but it's like, be careful what you ask for kind of thing.
You know what I mean?
Um, I believe in all that.
I believe that you can get what you want.
I'm in full belief of that.
But what I know is that I already experienced that and I asked for those things.
I asked for the bike, and I asked for the cloud, and I asked for the helmets, and I asked for all this.
And.
Wasn'T until again I had kids that I was like, there is nothing in this moment that is better than this, right?
And, um, so I got what I asked for, and then I got what was truly meant for me.
And what was truly meant for me was to be a.
Um.
And then I was like, okay, so I want to know what that purpose is, right?
Not what I have believed to make of my own purpose.
You know what I mean?
Because I.
Bro, it can happen.
I've seen it, like I said.
But, uh, why is it that these men that do scripture, and I mean really do do scriptures?
There's this dude, Philip Anthony Mitchell, who's just a dog, bro.
He was an ex drug dealer, and he is just a dog for scripture.
And he just has the end of the same.
It's like ET but like on steroids board.
Like, and like, he's calling out the truth.
Like, he's reading stuff that other preachers shy away from.
Because it's like, oh, I don't want to upset people on the gram and on YouTube.
And I don't.
We don't want to get people out of the doors that don't want to do tithing anymore.
He's reading the truth.
And within that, it is just the most powerful and beautiful thing.
But I mean, bro, why is it that these guys have so m.
Like, you see him have so much fulfillment.
He.
I remember a story.
He was on a mission trip and he had a revelation.
Ever since he came back, he's never worn a color.
He wears all black.
He doesn't want to draw attention himself.
He calls it a uniform.
He's like, this is my uniform.
This is why I believe I'm not supposed to draw attention to myself.
I'm supposed to show up.
This is a job for me, right?
But it's like, why do those men feel so.
Like they seem so fulfilled, but all these dudes with the this and that that and the flashy and the colors and the pink shirts, and there's nothing to do with fashion, right?
But it's like.
But when you're, like, doing this thing to stand out or to.
To be me or to people better know me when I, uh, pull up and all this, like, why is those things.
Why does it seem like those things are always changing, right?
And like, being like, well, bro, you just bought the other car, like, last week.
Like, it's just like, what.
Like, what the hell?
Like, I thought you.
Like.
And it's like, you were doing that, now you're doing this.
And it's like, because they're trying to find something, a foundation to stand on.
And all the foundations that they're building on are.
Are not solid.
But then you see the men that have those things, but they're rooted in.
In something solid.
They don't Stand on that, right?
Like, bro, I.
I heard an ET Thing he said one time.
He said, why you don't think I don't post none of my cars?
You don't think I have a Rolls Royce?
He said, because I don't want people to go to the dealership when they need to go to the Bible.
Um, yeah, dude.
Well.
Well, I mean, how much does our culture mess up with trying to.
We puts all of our energy into the image of success instead of like, learning what success could really mean for us as an individual.
I mean, as you mentioned, the fashion thing, uh, it's.
I can relate with that, man.
I think when it.
When I was, you know, at my most hurt inside, I was trying to be the loudest outside with my fashion.
You were doing the most.
The hair and the this and the glasses and the piercings and the this.
And yeah, I don't want attention.
I even, I mean, I mean, if people listening might remember I made.
I had like a little like an accidental clothing line for a few months.
I made these.
You matter, uh, hoodies, they have the suicide number on the back.
In my perception of even that is completely different.
Like, I wouldn't even wear that now because I didn't realize it back then.
I was trying to make a statement about myself or the person who wants to wear.
Like, I support suicide rather than, like, really dealing with what's going on inside to where I don't have to run around wearing a shirt like, ask me about suicide.
I'll teach you everything.
I'm a pastor about it.
And instead, yeah, I can just heal from those things, have my real experience, and then, you know, what up.
Sometimes, once in a while, every six months, three months, whatever, I'm at work having a convo with a young guy, 22 years old, and he's going through exactly what I went through.
And I didn't need to wear a hoodie, saying, ask me about it.
I would just showed up and I was present in my life.
Exactly.
And those.
And then, uh, this is what scripture says.
That's a divine appointment, right?
Like, it's like you're supposed to be right where you're supposed to be.
But no, I love that, bro.
But honestly, I really love the idea of mixing cultured people with this because we're the guys that can connect with people.
Right?
Um, like there's, ah.
I feel like a lot of preachers have a hard time connecting with the younger generation because all these guys know is that they've been a preacher their whole life, right?
It's like, but where are the guys like me, right, that have been encapsulated in sin and just have been in the deepest depths of sex and just all these types of things?
And then going.
There's a.
There's a quote that says that.
That God doesn't call the qualified.
He qualifies the call, right?
And it's like, the fact that you're a disaster.
Uh, the fact that you're.
The fact that you're a disaster actually means you're called, right?
Because it's.
This is.
We are more related.
This is psychological from a.
From a positive standpoint and a negative standpoint.
If you, um, hire a guy at a Ferrari dealership, you say, hey, dude, I'm gonna give you this key to this car.
You can drive it and you can drive it.
It's yours if you sell this many X cars a month.
And if you don't, I'm gonna take it away.
He sells those cars.
If you hire him and you say, hey, if you sell this many cars, I'm gonna give you this car, he may hit it, he may not.
But I guarantee, once he's driving that thing, he will hold on to it, right?
And so, um, we are more connected, and we dive more towards pain, right?
Because that would be something taken away from me, and that's considered pain.
What I'm getting at is, psychologically, we communicate better through pain, right?
The guys that.
That, like, make it financially, they.
There's this mutual respect there because they're like, oh, I know what I went through.
Like, and he went.
And he went like, he.
That means he went through that too, right?
And that's where you see the camaraderie within that.
You're like, wow, rich people always hang out with each other.
It's like, bro, it's.
It's a camaraderie there because it's like, you don't know what it's like to build something like this, right?
Military people going through the same stuff.
So it's the same thing with.
Kind of.
What I'm saying is, that's why I love being in this position, because when I'm like, oh, man, I know.
I know where you are like.
And when I speak, people are like, God, I feel that, like, now I'm connected to you.
Think about it.
You listen to people you respect, right?
You're like, yeah, you've been a preacher your whole life, bro.
Come on.
Like, nobody wants to hear all that, but it's like, oh, Nate was.
I remember when he was at the thing I remember he's at the l.
Uh, the.
The LCC party.
And.
And he was breaking the bottles over the thing because his.
His ex girlfriend is making out with some.
Some dude, and he cheated on her, but now she's with somebody else, but he's pissed off for some reason.
Drunk breaking bottles.
Yeah.
That same guy.
Yeah, that same guy.
Yeah.
Now he wants to talk about this.
Like.
Or like, bro, I mean, being as good as I am on the bike, like, it's automatic respect.
These people.
I, uh, have these people's respect.
So it's like, yeah, maybe if Joe Schmo.
That's not, uh, good.
They don't want to hear what he has to say.
But 90 of people don't care about what I'm talking about now.
But the 10%, Jesus says, I'll leave the 99 to save the 1, right?
So if I can get 1%, if I can get one person, bro, think about that.
Branch out, right?
That's why parenting is so important to me and why I'm telling.
I'm trying to tell people, especially parents, there's nothing more important in this life you'll do than to be a parent.
Think of the branch out.
That happens.
My son, okay?
I'm having a lot of kids, bro.
I don't know why my wife thinks about that, but I'm having a lot of kids.
Yeah, we have three.
We have.
She says four.
She said she's fine with four.
I would like far more than five.
Okay?
But think about that, okay?
Think about how if I just impact my son and I just give him everything he needs to go out and just face these battles and to live a good life and to be a good man.
Then he has five kids, hopefully, right?
Then my daughter has five kids, hopefully.
Then my other daughter has five kids, hopefully.
And then they go out and they be like me, and they want to be like, you know what I was.
I'm a.
I'm a little shy to talk about this because it's not my normal MO and it's mostly like, yeah, nasty.
Nay saved the day.
But this is what actually changed my life, and I want to share it with you.
Imagine my 25, this little.
Little minions go out and do that, and then how many lives they change.
Yeah.
Okay.
So this is what the meaning of life is.
We just have got it confused.
M.
Well, uh, have you heard of Ken Wilbur?
He's like a spiritual.
He writes, um, like, integral theory.
He's a strange.
He's like a bald dude.
He wears a wig Nowadays he's like, he's.
It's funny to see him.
But anyway, he, uh, he talks about, um.
You know, in spiritual awakening, there is, uh, like, this spiritual evolution that becomes apparent.
Like, you wake up to whatever your version of your spiritual awakening is.
Some people, their spiritual awakening is just, like, holy.
The government, like, gave me a name when I was like, this isn't my name.
I was given this name.
The government literally, like, sometimes it's just that level.
But any sort of awakening, especially spiritual awakening, it seems it's become so apparent.
Oh, yeah, evolution is happening.
And I had to become aware of those things that I was unconscious to.
Of course I'm.
I'm developing.
I'm growing.
When I'm 60 years old, I'm going to be a whole totally different person.
Right.
But, um, along with that awakening, something that Ken Wilber points out that it's just so juicy to me is spiritual maturing, spiritual growing up, like.
And it's something that we actually have to put effort into.
It's like, you know, as guys, we come a certain age, you know, you get 14, 15, whatever, you hit puberty, your body just does this, and then you're along for the ride and your personality changes.
Right.
I think I've heard this.
Yeah, yeah.
So the universe does this.
This.
It's like, without, like.
And then you got to change yourself to, like, biology.
Yeah, yeah.
All these things.
Right.
It's.
Biology is the automatic.
Yeah, yeah.
But there's also so.
And just we could freaking become blind and, like, turn an eye, uh, Turn.
Turn a blind eye to the fact that we actually have to insert, uh, a, uh, growing up, a maturing of our spiritual selves too.
And that doesn't just happen.
Our society doesn't have, like, rituals and traditions that really allow that to happen.
So if we never assume, assert our own authority over it, we might be 48 years old and we're still crying about the, like, when that guy took away our yellow kickball and when we were 13.
Yeah.
You know, so anyway, there's 100%, bro.
There's a scripture that says, um, how long?
It says.
This is the translation I have is the new English, like, new nlt, which is like the very, very, very, like, English version of it.
But in mine it says, you simpletons, how long will you be simple?
And it's like, that's how I look at, like, the way that we're living now.
Right?
This life is about depth, bro.
Like I said, when I think about money, I don't think about money, bro, I don't think about stuff.
I think about if I make enough, I can buy the, the time to feel my son's rib cage, bro.
Like, and I think, and I think, and people will be like.
And people that are sleeping will be like, this guy is a, is a, uh, psychopath.
This guy is nuts.
This guy's off his rocker.
He needs meds, he needs help.
Guess what?
I already took them.
They didn't work.
Work.
Um, he.
This is the level of depth that you, that you gotta grasp to be able to like, really unlock what this life is, bro.
And it truly is just about giving everything for something, right?
And I think that's where the happy men, quote, unquote, happy.
That's where the happy men are, is fighting for a cause, right?
And that's why I was talking about the war.
You know, 50 years ago, these kids were like, bro, these kids know as soon as I jump off this boat, I'm getting shot in the head.
They were, they were doing it anyways.
Yeah.
Ah.
And.
And the craziest part is, is again, how much new age has changed.
It was for no glory.
Nobody knew who these guys were.
They didn't get martyred, they didn't go in the paper.
Sure, there was like a big ass list of all these kids that risked their life, but it was like they weren't heroes.
They were doing what they were supposed to do.
We need, especially as men, is to get back to doing what we're supposed to do.
Okay.
I sent this.
Um, this is for my men's group.
A group, uh, a message in the chat the other day.
Most of the stuff that we're supposed to do, we will never receive credit for.
But that's what you're supposed to do, right?
It's like planting a tree.
You'll probably never see that tree ever reach its full potential.
And that's the same idea I'm talking about with being a man.
Being a father and raising children is to bury and plant fruit that you never ever see.
and then instill in your son to do the same thing.
And that's how you create strong generations.
And I'm going to tell you exactly why I believe that right now more than ever, this is the most important thing that any father, any man can be doing is investing not into it, his career, but into his family, into his children.
And if you have a son, investing in your son, because I'm telling you, with AI and all the that's going on right now, this world, as generations gonna go on, is Going to get harder and harder and harder to navigate mentally and spiritually.
If you are not raising dogs, your lineage is doomed.
I'm telling you that right now.
I'm calling my shot.
It's the 20th of January 25th, 2025.
If you are not raising warriors in your homes, sons and daughters, that, um, that I have discernment of
I'm not doing this, I'm not doing that.
I'm not going there.
I'm not putting myself on the Internet to do this or do that.
Your lineage is doomed.
I'm saying that right now.
AI is, is.
AI is literally a two day old baby.
And it's already the scariest show I've ever seen in my life.
Yeah, pretty much every day it advances in  a way that we couldn't fathom the week before.
I saw something the other day that said that AI is already done with us.
Like, people think like, oh, this is so dangerous.
AI is learning from us.
No, AI is already done learning from us.
It's been done learning from us.
From the first couple months, it's.
It already gathered everything that it needed from all humans.
Now it's building upon its own thing.
So again, we are headed to what I see, towards Wally.
You remember Wally?
I love Wally.
Okay, so that movie, that movie, that's where we're headed.
So again, if you don't want to get swallowed up, if you don't want to see your generations get swallowed up, you need to be raising dogs.
Well, I, uh, mean, it's actually interesting to think.
I think you are touching on a vibration that is, uh, present in the culture.
I think, uh, the last few months we've seen a lot more like dudes less afraid to say things out loud, um, more like encouraging each other, like, stand up, um, you know, don't.
Like nobody's coming to save you.
That, that whole thing has seemed like the last few months, like people are really unafraid of that.
And I think it's important, I think it's useful.
And I think like, the bottom line is our young men need people to look up to.
What do you.
What are you doing?
You know, like.
Yeah, and real quick, before you skip that, I want to touch on that because there is a very fine line.
And this is where, like you said, there's been a big thing of men standing up to do this.
If you are involved in this stuff on the Internet, you need to have discernment.
Why?
Because I saw one of the biggest men's pages that I've ever seen.
And every single piece of content that goes viral is about being a sad boy.
No one cares about us.
No one cares about our feelings.
And these are the most viral posts.
And on top of that, this guy's selling something.
On top of that, huh?
So he's doing sad boy going viral and then selling something.
This does not serve you.
This keeps you exactly where you are.
Guess what we're gonna do?
We're all gonna get together, we're all gonna talk about how hard it is, and that's where we're gonna stay.
Guess what?
Find our identity there.
Thank you.
Okay, so a lot of as much as you believe that some of this.
That again, there goes the pain.
What did I say?
It's relative.
We relate to it because of the pain.
But what is the after?
Right?
This is exactly what I was saying before.
Most people don't see progress in life because they stop at the pain.
He, man, yeah.
I love this dude's page, bro.
He's always posting these videos.
It's like, dude, there was this guy that I even bought his sweatshirt.
I had to unfollow him because everything about was that it's so hard not to be an alcoholic.
Uh, I message him, I'm like, you gotta stop being a bro.
Like, you either want this or you want that.
You either want to be a stand up guy and be a good dad, and this is it, bro.
I firmly believe you can change your life in an instant.
Imagine, bro.
Uh, this is.
Everything is metaphorical, is so beautiful.
Okay?
Imagine for anybody.
And I have not yet.
I need to be baptized.
We believe as Christians, when you get baptized, you get dipped in the water, you get pulled up, you're fully renewed.
Everything is renewed, right?
If I'm created in God's image, which scripture says, so why can I not snap my fingers, close my eyes, open them, and I'm a completely new person.
Why is that not possible?
This thing.
Here's your affirmations.
This thing no longer has a hold of me.
Okay?
If most of the time, a lot of our actions don't align with what we say we want, right?
So if I say I want to be a good dad, I want to be this, I want to be that, I want, blah, blah, blah, why am I fighting this thing?
And then I realize I'm like, oh, you're selling sweatshirts.
Oh, these videos go viral.
Oh, and it's like this corny ass, like, oh, I really want to tell my wife how I'm doing, but.
And just pulls up like this white mask over his face.
Better walk out the door.
It's like that.
Stop watching this content.
This does not serve you.
Okay, again, most people cannot be honest enough with themselves or even want to hear me say this because you probably bought his sweatshirt that watch the chain.
Do I believe that he probably had good intentions starting out?
Absolutely.
Because that spoke to somebody and they maybe got it together, but this continuous over and over and over and over again.
Guess what?
I was reading the same scripture the other day and scripture says, um, so sorry, um, got to pull it.
God blesses those who.
Whose hearts are pure.
Okay, so what I wanted to say with that is people believe that our actions are what's on trial.
No, your heart is on trial.
And guess what?
Nobody can see that but you.
Right?
So even if the intention.
And again, this is for men have discernment.
Even if the intention with whatever this guy had going on started out good.
Hey, I'm dealing with this.
I want to share it, I'm getting through it.
But then all of a sudden when you start to see this trend.
Oh, weird.
There's.
There's, oh, oh, he's got.
Oh, he's got some stuff for sale.
Weird.
Oh, all these sad boy videos go viral.
Oh, weird.
They're all of a sudden he stopped posting his progress and he's replaying the most viral videos and he's recording them in a different way.
Where's the progress, my guy?
But guess what?
Most people, the sheep, the 99, they don't want to see progress.
They want to see somebody where they're at.
Which means it's what Jake Relatable.
You see the chain here?
So I pray that that man has a clean heart.
That's what I pray for, right?
So that is another one of my focuses because I realize I'm raising my children here.
I'm doing this, I'm doing good, right?
But it's like, but where is my heart at?
And I think that if this is where the true success actually lies is knowing even though I'm doing good actions, right?
Um, even though I'm giving money to people on the street, nobody knows that.
Ah, Bible says I'm not supposed to tell anybody I'm doing that.
Bible says I'm not supposed to put that on the Internet.
That.
Right?
What is the intention?
Did you give the money away because you thought it was a good idea?
But yeah, uh, why, why do we record it?
Why do we have to do that?
So the action is in the right, but that's the actions are not being judged, the heart is being judged.
Right?
So that uh, that was just the metaphor of I'm trying to do everything, even in my good deeds as I raised my son and my daughter and my other daughter and I be a good husband to my wife, Lord help me do that.
Um, be a good husband to my wife.
That I'm not doing this for my own thing.
Like, look at me, look what I've done with my kids, right?
But this can only happen.
And my friends will tell you, Brandon will tell you I am the most self accountable person ever.
Even when things are going right, I'm like, what am I doing wrong here?
Right?
Like, and so most people would look at even Brandon, he's like, dog, why are you so hard on yourself?
I'm like, because I just know accountability is the way like.
And again, extreme, intense accountability, right?
I don't want people to look at me and go, oh yeah, your kids are this and your kids are that.
And we go, yeah, well that's why I'm doing it.
No, I want my heart to be pure.
So then when this branch out happens, it happens in good faith, right?
It doesn't happen because it was a show.
You know what I mean?
Well, do you?
Okay, so what I think that people, he kind of already said it earlier but like people put their energy into their image so much and I've been there, you've been there.
How do we, how do we notice when we're doing that?
How do we notice when we're like.
It'S kind of that same extreme accountability, bro.
Have you ever seen extreme accountability?
Like I feel like I'm going to use females just because I feel like they're an easy low hanging fruit example.
Like you watch videos of like, like a drunk girl being recorded on you her party street or whatever.
Like, like the hawk to a situation.
Um, like suddenly they are a person, they're an expression of who they are.
And then suddenly they realize someone's recording them in a different version.
A different person comes online, a different person shows up and, and all of us have that just as humans.
Like, you know, back in the day there was radio voice and like ladies and gentlemen.
But like if I started doing that to you right now, you'd be like, what do you like, that's weird.
So there is a level of like when you are aware that the camera's on you, you have an image that is going to be long lasting, you have an awareness of it.
But I think a, that that's Them.
So I love where you're going with this.
I love where you're going with this.
Go ahead.
So how do we realize when we're fooling ourselves into putting our energy into our image instead of.
Our image is an afterthought of something.
People can judge us for later if they want, but we did the work.
Then they talk about, um, who cares what the image is?
It's an afterthought.
Yeah.
So, Jake, I, I'm still on the same idea that, that everything.
I don't know if I'm gonna explain this right, but all the things that are supposed to happen.
Uh, okay, what?
I don't know how I've been explaining this whole entire journey of, like, it's the same thing, right?
The same vibe or whatever when the camera's on you.
I like that.
I act like that all the time.
Why?
Because.
What?
I want somebody to see this.
That is how you can hold accountability, right?
So, uh, check this out.
Here's a metaphor.
I, I literally live my life in metaphor, okay?
Because, uh, if I don't, I, I.
There is no anymore for me in this moment.
Back up against the wall.
I don't have that, but I need that for my, for my male spirit.
I need that, right?
So imagine this.
Imagine I'm a guy.
It's an inspirational guy on Instagram.
I go at 6am I go to the track, I take a little video of my feet running, and then I stop and get in the car.
But there's a camera on me, okay?
If my heart is pure, I don't need the camera on me.
But if my heart is pure, I'm putting in that mile, right?
I'm not doing that.
Uh, cool.
All right.
Cool.
All right, cool.
Let's get in the car.
Okay.
Use that, that thing that you just said.
Use that.
I, I, the other, uh, was, like, a couple months ago, um, my son Jet was.
And, and we're waffling with this, right?
We're the first generation that is of gentle parenting, of.
Right.
This whole new idea that people got going on and all this kind of stuff.
We're waffling with ideas from scripture, modern ways of parent.
We're.
We're getting our footing, right?
And, um, for the first four years now, we have not spanked one of our children.
Um, I want to find a different way to do it.
I'm also not opposed to it at the same time.
Why, Jake?
Because when we go out as men and we do dumb, we get smacked in the mouth, right?
Let's be honest.
Right.
Um, but I.
I like, um.
So where I'm getting at with that is the other day, my son was a little rough with my daughter, and I grabbed him by the arm, and I remember grabbing him pretty hard.
And again, here's the accountability and here's the pure heart.
Most other people would have been, like, totally justified.
Not a big deal, bro.
M.
Like, you didn't even hurt him.
You just yanked him over.
But in that moment, I felt anger.
That's not okay.
So if I had a camera on me, would I want somebody to see that?
No, I wouldn't.
So that thing that you just said can actually be used as a beautiful thing to actually guide your life and help you is how would I want people to see me?
How would I.
How would I want this story to go?
How would I want this movie to play out?
Right?
I always say, make the decision that tells the best story, right?
So in this moment, this guy, imagine, you know, we're working in a movie, right?
I said this in my.
My speech a couple years ago.
You get all the way up to the.
To the part where it's like, here we go.
Is.
Here's me, right?
Is the guy gonna quit the job?
He hates it.
He's miserable, dude.
We're building a fantastic story here, right?
And then he quits his job, and then he retreats and goes back to a different job.
No one's reading that, bro.
No one's gonna read that.
Not only is no one gonna read that or watch that.
I want to inspire my son, right?
I want him to be like, what did you do in this situation?
My.
One of my biggest fears is saying, I don't know.
I don't know what you should do.
I don't know.
Never been there, never tried that, right?
Again, I feel like.
And the only and everything in life is a gamble, bro, right?
Because if I go and do all these things and exhaust myself in every area to gain this wisdom and help guide him, we could argue that he does no self discovery and he could end up being soft.
That is a risk.
But at the same time, if I do well enough, he will also take the.
The pattern of doing the same exact thing for his own life, then to pass it on to his son, right?
So that's.
That's kind of where I'm at with it.
Uh, but with this whole idea that you're talking about of, um, how do we switch that?
I think you literally using.
You set the stage for, like, the cameras on you for a perfect answer, bro.
Like, the camera's on you.
How do you want to be seen?
Like, think about it.
We do so many things.
I always say people got full closets and empty fridges.
You care how you.
You.
You care how you've seen.
But think about what's actually most important.
You're not.
You know what I mean?
People got a closet for full of Jordans, and they have orange juice and Rockstar in the fridge, and that's it.
Yeah.
It makes me think of those videos.
Sometimes I'll get fed videos of, um.
And I.
I've got to realize it's because I'm spending time watching them, so they're feeding them to me.
But, uh, like, people going to get their nails done, and they're just like, I don't got any money, though.
Yeah.
Literally, like, what.
What are you doing at the nail salon?
Are you out of your mind?
But, like, in that moment, you could hear them, like, their nails records, and you could hear that person.
And hey, for all I know is probably like a skit just to get.
Of course.
But, um, they're.
They're not taking accountability.
They're like, well, so I don't have the money.
What are you gonna do?
Like, there's just this constant, like, not taking accountability for the situation they're in.
And, um, I just think, like, the more you bury yourself underneath that, the harder and harder it is to.
To get out from underneath it.
Dude, it's like, stop putting your energy into things that don't serve you.
Like, serving the image of you is not the same thing as serving you.
But I do.
Like what you said.
Exactly.
But that right there.
Yeah, run that back, like, because that's exactly it.
And also, too, I think, again, if you're not awake, you don't understand that that story you just use is not a story about finances.
No, it's not.
It's about what the actions that you take that show, um, atomic habits.
Every action you take is a vote for the person you want to be.
Think that's extremely.
And again, correlate that to what we were just talking about with the movie thing.
Okay?
What?
Like, if, if, if.
If this is a bottle, right?
If this is booze and I raise this, what action?
What does this say?
Right?
People are, uh, you're not.
We're not thinking like that.
That.
Right?
If I, if I, if I, you know, if I'm faithful, but I'm looking at girls on Instagram.
What does that action say?
Right?
This.
And again, it only happens with extreme accountability.
That is the only thing that's worked for me, right?
I had a big ego before.
I had my business, but I had no business.
What am I doing wrong?
I know I'm good at my skill set, but I have no business.
But for the longest time, it wasn't my fault.
It was that they were cheap or they couldn't afford me, or they didn't want to pay this or they didn't want to pay that, or they're stupid because they don't want to use me.
They want to use somebody else.
Guess who was losing the entire time?
Me.
I was the one losing.
They weren't losing.
They were getting their videos done.
Those clients were getting their videos done by somebody else.
So that's the only thing that helped me make progress was extreme accountability.
So now I am overly accountable for every situ, even when things are good, right?
And here's an extreme situation.
Three months ago, I, uh, had the biggest month I ever had in my life financially.
Uh, and as sweet as it was, I sat down and I asked God, if this is not the motion that you intend for me to have, please remove it from my life.
And that next month, I lost both of my biggest clients.
I don't have any.
I don't have an issue with that.
Why?
Because I asked for it.
Right?
And I asked for it with good intention.
Okay?
So it's just so deep, bro.
It's so deep.
And.
And I.
I don't want to ramble, and I don't want to talk so much about myself, but I.
I think that the only way to truly go.
Hey, you should try this.
Is to say, this is where I was.
This is how I was feeling.
This is kind of where I'm at now.
And this was the.
The.
This bridge, the gap.
You know what I mean?
So, um, I hope that we did a good job of that.
I really do.
Um.
But, yeah, I don't know.
I mean, yeah, I.
I think it comes through, man.
I think, um, I mean, like you said before multiple times, um, you know, I'm not.
I'm not a pastor.
I'm a stunt writer.
You know, I'm.
I'm just a freaking DJ who enjoys podcasting, and I like poetry and stuff.
And I.
I think about myself.
Myself a lot.
And, uh, I noticed that that's selfish.
And so I try to take.
Okay, I think about myself a lot.
How can I take what I've learned about myself, my own life lessons, and repackage them in my rambling to other people and maybe positively impact someone else.
So I think being upfront with it and you know, it's also pretty easy, like neither of us are selling anything there.
I don't have a sales funnel for you to go down.
Uh, if I did, I'd tell you about it, like link below, but I don't have one.
So.
Yeah, facts, yeah, I think that does come through, man.
I think just, just I, I, I contemplate the podcast space a lot because I go through multiple months sometimes where I'm like, man, podcast like Grown 30 Year Old Men.
Podcasting is somehow cringe as all heck sometimes.
And uh, then, and then I'll go through like the next month and I'll be listening to my, like listen to other people on podcasts and I'll be so freaking inspired.
And they say the right thing at the right time and I'm like, oh yeah, like, yeah, it could be cheesy but uh, it's good intention and that comes through.
I mean bro, I, I don't even look at it like that.
I really look at it as just like, like two dudes sitting down and having a conversation and it, I, I think the only time it's cringy, bro, I really do is when there's no value.
I really, I really do.
And that's why I tried my absolute best in here.
And I hope anybody listens to it, heard my heart that I try to lead with value here because that's when it is, it's like when you're just talking about very um, surface level, substance type of things.
Obviously if you're on a financial podcast, you're going to talk about money, right?
If you're on a sales podcast, you're going to talk about sales, but you're in the, the quote unquote mental health space.
Right.
So I feel like again, if we're just on here talking about our problems with no solution or how do we, how do we not, how do we work through this or you know, challenging some narratives for people to open their perspective.
I feel like you've done your job and it's not um, corny, you know.
I mean, I think you said that nicely.
I think that's true.
I think, um, yeah.
And that's what the podcast has turned into me is I, I show up.
And I, I think if you're just selling, I think if you're quote unquote, selling air, like, like we're just talking nonsense.
Yeah.
And yeah, you're probably on the path of like being corny, you know what I mean?
But I don't think you do that, bro.
Yeah, like, I don't have a, uh.
I.
I'm not fooled to think that I'm, like, that interesting that I can just go and ramble, and it's actually important.
Like, I, you know, I try to share things that I'm learning about and try to pull those out of other people that are sitting across from me, so.
I think you did good, man.
Dude, it was, um.
It's good to catch up, bro.
I think.
Yeah, no kidding, bro.
I had a lot to say, bro.
I always have a lot to say to say, but.
Yeah, I'm never a man short for words, bro.
I'm never a man short for words.
Well, good thing, because, uh, I.
I work in the world of microphones, so.
You know how we're talking.
It's.
It's good to.
Good to have a.
Have, uh, such a.
A good voice and a positive influence for people and.
And be able to kind of send that megaphone out to people who will listen and, you know, maybe they'll come out a better version of themselves after they listen to our rambling and.
Appreciate it, bro.
I appreciate it.
Yeah.
Ah, I appreciate you having me on, bro.
All right, brother.
Well, hey, um, all the love.
We'll be in touch, bro.
And listeners, uh, take care of yourselves.
You know the deal.
Have you stressed today?
Have you drank some water?
Yeah.
Where's your gratitude?
Uh, Nate, physical activity.
Yes, please, for the love of gosh, get your body moving.
Um, I don't know if you got.
If you got a scripture or anything that you want to leave us with, but I have the intuition to have you guide us out, my friend.
Oh, man.
Okay.
Um.
Wow, bro.
Um, so.
Jeez.
This man put me on, um, on the spot right here.
Um, I want to talk to.
I feel like, kind, um, of that whole thing.
I just maybe round out a little bit of what we talked about.
Men, um, have really been on my heart lately because I feel like.
Like the world asks so much of men, right?
You need to be this, you need to be that.
You need to be doing this.
Not only is it asked, it's actually expected.
And if it's not expected, you know, you're.
You're less than.
Right?
And I want to let every man know, especially my.
My guys that are fathers going to be fathers, husbands, all these things that there is.
Everyone's in a different place in their journey.
And when I say that, I mean that very, very deeply as far as.
Even in their lineage.
Right.
There is problems that have Been neglected by men before you that need to be stalled.
If you do not solve them, they will passed on and passed on and passed on, right?
So sometimes other men have been put in position for them to grab.
Grab the lit torch and run it straight into millions, right?
And then there's other guys that don't even know where the torch is or the torch is wet or there's no lighter.
And they got, uh.
And they're doing all these things, and they spend years and years and years of this life trying to even get the torch lit.
And then guess what?
Then they go and pass it on to their son, who then goes and runs it up, right?
And so if you are a man in this life, if you never make a million dollars, if you never dream that, have that dream house or that thing, if the last thing that you ever do and the only thing in this physical life that you hang your hat on is that you led your family down the narrow path and that you were the first people in your generation to break all these things and go to the way.
The truth and the light.
You have succeeded.
And that's what I feel like has been on my heart a lot, is because we're so worried about the external things.
We're not understanding, that if we neglect to even get the foundation built, nothing will stand after you go.
And guess what?
Then you have no control of it once you're gone.
Bravo, man.
Beautifully said.
Thank you for that.
Appreciate it, bro.
All right, Nate, I'll talk to you soon, man.
All the love.
Um, yeah, man, just to keep you on the hook.
It was so great to talk to you, man.
I'll be in touch.
Peace out, everybody.
Uh, see you.
Thanks, guys.
At what age should we learn to.
Have better conversations with ourselves?
Knowledge is power.
Reality is.